https://github.com/probinso

Personal Statement

I love to work on hard problems and value the knowlege needed to generate solutions in new domains. I am an adaptable engineer, whose work history spans products and research in machine learning, software engineering, scientific computing, and computer securities.

Skills/Experience :

Python C, C++ TDD Linux

R, dplyr $\mathbb{E}T_{F}X$ Git Ticketing Systems

Work Experience ___

Graduate Research OHSU/ACO - Machine Learning in Marine Acoustics

Acted as project lead and managed communication in a remote environment without supervision Researched deep anomaly detectors, to index bioacoustic events from a 10 year audio track Measured effects of adaptive spectral subtraction, for audio denoising, on model accuracy Developed ACOio, an intuitive ACO track explorer, to rejuvenate data access for researchers

Technologies: Python, ACOio, Keras, tensorflow, scipy.signal, Jupyter

HappyWhale

- Staff Software Engineer

March 2019 - present

Worked as software developer in nimble small team in both a remote and onsite environment Developed SciDir, a cross platform tablet application for managing citizen-science projects Maintained and contributed to user tools for individual whale identification and tracking

Technologies: NativeScript, Angular, node.js, Android, PostgreSQL, Java

- Graduate Data Science Intern June 2018 - Sept. 2018 NASA Jet Propulsion Lab

Fully specified programmatic solution from use-case meetings with top NASA/JPL employees Designed & developed Expert Modeling/Recommender System, by extending the Author-Topic-Model Implemented stable/principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation Open Source contributions to the gensim natural language processing library

Technologies: Python, nltk, gensim, pyLDAvis, pandas, Jupyter

- Research Assistant OHSU Fair Neuroimaging Lab

Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Contributed to microbiome population analytics tools, to study female reproductive system Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported and FMRI data, on AHDH/ASD studies Acted as OSS and Securities lead, developing, training and enforcing best practices

Technologies: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan, GitLab, Docker

- Remote Contractor/Consultant Nov. 2015 - Aug. 2018 RGB Optics (Part Time)

Developed custom photo image processing tools and pipelines for low cost spectral analysis Authored educational material in light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Developed natural language processing tools to organize and explore Myeloma clinical trials Provided technology tutorials and consulting on code optimization, NLP, and image processing

Technologies: Python, numpy, skimage, AWS, ponyorm, PostgreSQL, ZenHub, CliNER

- R&D Software Engineer April 2014 - Dec 2015 Galois Inc.

Developed processing pipelines and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Helped run professional trainings to disseminate new probabilistic programming languages Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track

Technologies: Python, SLURM, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker, Jira, Basecamp

Neato Projects ____

Topic modeling and applications, a presentation for non-statisticians beamer, MTEX Workshop collaborative introduction to GitHub and slides markdown, bash, github.api Distributed Morphological Watersheding Algorithms pyspark, numpy, ndimage, Python Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask, numpy, nltk, sklearn, Python Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Sagemath Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Sagemath, Erlang

Education

Oregon Health Science University

Machine Learning

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

Courses :

Analysis of Sequences
Artificial Intelligence
Computing Ethics
Deep Learning
Image Processing
Information Retrieval
Problem Solving with Large Clusters

Western Washington University

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor June 2012

Courses :

Unix Software Development
Windows Software Development
Operating Systems
Computer Networks
Software Project Requirements Analysis
Software Project Design
Software Project Implementation
Analysis of Algorithms

Electives :

Abstract Algebra
Artificial Intelligence
Computer Architecture
Computer Graphics
Cryptography & Elliptic Curves
Elementary Real Analysis

Natural Language Processing
Machine Learning
Machine Learning, Advanced Topics
Signal Processing, Speech
Signal Processing, Advanced Topics
Univariate Statistical Analysis
Statistical Methods

Computer Science & Cryptography

Linear/Non-Linear Data Structures
Discrete Structures
Formal Languages/Automata
Programming Languages
Concurrent Programming
Computer Organization I/II
Probability and Statistical Inference
Object-Oriented Programming in C++

Functional Programming
Homomorphic Encryption Systems
Linear Algebra I/II
Natural Language Processing
Number Theory
Ordinary Differential Equations